Finding Aid for the Howard Besser Museum Educational Site Licensing Project Papers, 1983, 1992-1999, and undated IA20019
Institutional Records and Archives
- Publications and presentations, 1995-1999; Series IV.; 0.4 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  - Working copies, Visual Resources, vol. 14 no. 4, 1999; [3 files] (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 12-14)
- Administrative records, 1995-1999; undated; Series V.; 0.54 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
  These records are arranged by subject.
  Papers consist of minutes, agendas, reports, invoices, contracts, press releases, forms, printed matter and photographs, 1995-1999 and undated, created or used by participants in the Museum Educational Site Licensing Project. The meeting minutes and agenda include information on the Project's Advisory Board—its members, meetings, and reports presented by Howard Besser. These records also include the official minutes of an MESL participant's meeting, and documents presented for discussion at a participant's meeting held in Santa Monica, California that deal with economic issues. Much of the budget and expense information records pertain to the preparation of budget reports for the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation. The personnel records are primarily concerned with the hiring and employment of Beth Sandore, Coordinator, Digital Imaging Initiative and Associate Professor, University of Illinois, as a consultant to assist with the evaluation process.
  For additional information on the Santa Monica participant's meetings, see also Series II. Gathered data.
  - Meeting minutes and agenda:
    - Advisory Board invitations, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 15)
    - Advisory committee, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 16)
    - Presentation to Advisory Board, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 17)
    - Revised report to Advisory Board, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 18)
    - Information for Mellon meeting, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 19)
    - Report to Advisory Board, November 18, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 20)
    - Advisory Board, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 21)
    - Advisory Board materials, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 22)
    - Advisory Board materials, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-9, Folder 23)
    - Official minutes, MESL meeting, December 1996; [2 files] (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 1-)
    - IP licensing and museum/university perceived needs, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 3)
  - Budget and expense information:
    - Letter to [Richard] Ekman, 1995; 1998,; undated (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 4)
      [Background budget materials.]
    - Prepping for [Richard] Ekman, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 5)
    - Distribution costs report, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 6)
    - Dollar awards to MESL universities, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 7)
    - Budget and expenses, 1996-1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 8)
    - Mellon expenses, 1996-1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 9)
    - Budget and cost information, 1997-1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 10)
    - Budget, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 11)
    - Crowne Plaza hotel information, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 12)
    - Letters and invoices re: distribution of final report, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 13)
    - Publishing information, 1999 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 14)
  - Personnel:
    - Associate Specialist hiring, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 15)
    - Hiring, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 16)
    - Consultant information, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 17)
    - Sandore contracts, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 18)
    - Sandore administrative, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 19)
    - Beth Sandore, consultant, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 20)
    - Personnel, undated (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous:
    - Short description of project, undated (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 22)
    - Press release, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 23)
    - Press releases, and Chronicle of Higher Education article, 1995; 1999 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 24)
    - Human subjects, policies, emails, 1995-1996; [3 files] (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 25-27)
    - Berkeley IRB, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous to file, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous emails, 1997-1998; [1 of 2] (Box 2002.IA.05-10, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous emails, 1997-1998; [2 of 2] (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous administrative records and notes, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous information, Santa Monica meeting, December 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 3)
    - NEH grant application guidelines, undated (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 4)
    - Art production, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 5)
    - Book recall and return receipts, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 6)
    - Scanning, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 7)
    - [48 unidentified color photographs], undated (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 8)
- Research and background materials, 1983; 1992,; 1994-1998,; undated; (bulk 1996-1998); Series VI.; 0.51 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  Papers consist of printed matter and correspondence, 1983, 1992, 1994-1998 and undated, collected by Howard Besser, Principal Investigator of the Museum Educational Site Licensing Project. The materials are primarily copies of articles and book chapters, used for background research for the development of the Project.
  - ARLIS/NA standards for art libraries and fine arts slide collections, 1983 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 9)
  - Cummings, Anthony, Marcia L. Witte, William G. Bowen, Laura O. Lazarus, Richard H. Ekman, University Libraries and Scholarly Communication (Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, November 1992) (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 10)
  - Research materials, 1994; 1996-1997; [2 files] (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 11-12)
  - Digital watermarking, 1995 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 13)
  - Virage, 1995 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 14)
  - "Cost Centers and Measures in the Networked Information Value Chain,", October 31, 1995 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 15)
  - "The Advances of Technology,", 1995 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 16)
  - Syllabi, 1995-1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 17)
  - Allerton Institute, research forum on digital libraries, 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 18)
  - "Steps Toward an Ecology of Infrastructure,", 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 19)
  - African Art and the Virtual Museum (University of Virginia syllabus), 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 20)
  - "Yale University Library's Project Open Book", 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 21)
  - Participant list, "Libraries, People and Change: A Research Forum on Digital Libraries,", 1996 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous articles and newsletters, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 23)
  - AMICO information, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 24)
  - AMICO launch meeting, 1997; [3 files] (Box 2002.IA.05-11, Folder 25-27)
  - Miscellaneous notes and research materials, 1997-1998; [2 files] (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 1-2)
  - Columbia slide library, 1996; 1998; [2 files] (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 3-4)
  - Log files, 1997 (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 5)
  - Museum Digital Licensing Collective, talk and information, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 6)
  - "The Making of American II Testbed Project White Paper,", 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 7)
  - Copyright and fair use town meeting program, 1998 (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 8)
  - Slide libraries–examples from the web, undated (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 9)
  - Digital show and tell agenda, undated (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 10)
  - Saska brochures, undated (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 11)
  - "Library Services in Theory and Context. Chapter 11: Allocation I: Resources, Priorities and Political Processes,", undated (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 12)
  - Graduate research questionnaire, undated (Box 2002.IA.05-12, Folder 13)